Guide to the Frank H. Golay papers, 1955-1983.
Golay, Frank H. papers, 1955-1983
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Frank H. Golay papers, 1955-1983.
14-10-2760
Frank H. Golay.
8 cubic ft.
Topical files, research notes, office files, correspondence, speeches, drafts of articles and other writings, and economic reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers include Golay's topical files concerning chiefly international economic development and relations, and Philippine development, history, and economics. Also, research notes, office files, correspondence, speeches, drafts of articles and other writings, and economic reports.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Economics, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers include Golay's topical files concerning chiefly international economic development and relations, and Philippine development, history, and economics. Also, research notes, office files, correspondence, speeches, drafts of articles and other writings, and economic reports.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Golay, Frank H.
Subjects:
Developing countries--Economic conditions.; Economic development--Philippines.; Economic development projects--Philippines.; International relations.; International economic relations.
Places:
Philippines--Economic conditions.; Philippines--Politics and government.; Philippines--History.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Some Costs of Philippine Politics - Various Versions (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Commercial Politics - Miscellaneous Items Collected, 1903-29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Philippines: Balance of Payments, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Basic Trade Data, 1905-40 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bureau of Customs Collections, 1898-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Fiscal Consequences of Payne/Aldrich (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Internal Revenue Collections, 1905-18 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Internal Revenue Taxation - Basic background, 1901-05 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Public Finance Date, Post 1915, Statistical Bulletin, 1920-34 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Land Tax (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Local Government - Tutelage and Autonomy, 1907-15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Local Government - Tutelage and Autonomy, 1903-07 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mobilization of Resources (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Mobilization of Resources, 1905-35 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Mobilization of Resources - Basic Tables (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Mobilization of Resources; Customs Duties, Taxation, 1904-16 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Spanish Period Data, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Philippines - Spanish Period, Export Trade, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Philippines - Foreign Trade, 1854-99 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Philippine Trade - Commodity Detail, 1937-38 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- R F Appointment, 1973-74 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Published Papers, 1958-65 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Published Papers, 1955-56 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Published Papers, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Published Papers, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Published Papers, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Philippines - Summary Data, Major Exports, 1899-1914 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Philippines - Summary Data, Minor Exports, 1900-40 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Philippines - Summary Data, Imparts, 1899-1940 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Philippines - Basic Data, Value of Imports and Exports (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Philippines - Base Period Data for Calculating Indexes, 1919-45 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Philippines - Miscellaneous Trade Indexes, 1900-67 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Philippines - Geographic Compositioin of Trade, 1899-1940 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Philippines: Summary Indexes, Foreign Trade (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Philippines: Trade Indexes, 19th Century, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Philippines: Summary Export Volume Indexes, 1899-1940 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Philippines: Summary Export Unit Value Indexes, 1899-1940 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Philippines: Summary Import Volume Indexes, 1899-1940 (Box 1, Folder 38-40)
- Philippines: 1903/1918 Census Reports (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Philippines: Basic Import Data. 1919-1940 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Philippines: Volume and Value of Exports, 1945-1960 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Philippines: Volume and Value of Imports, 1945-1960 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Philippines: Volume and Value of Imports, 1899-1920 (Box 1, Folder 45-47)
- Philippines: Volume and Value of Imports, 1990-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
- Philippines: Agriculture, Minerals and Ores (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1955-60 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1969-1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1071-1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Newspaper/Magazine Articles, 1960's (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Asia Society/AAS Conference, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Rizal Centennial at Cornell, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Annual Reports, Cornell Philippines Project, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Draft Paper: CSIS (Center for the Strategic and International Studies) Seminar on Philippines Economical Development, 1970[?] (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Wingspread Conference, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- The SEADAG Evaluation, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- The Golay Report, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- The Great Discontent: the State of Economic Development, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Task Force (McNeill), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Memo for Henry K., 1975 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Belmont Conference, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Background Paper, Belmont Conference, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- SEADAG Report: The Belmont Conference, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- U.S. Interests and Philippine Policy, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- CSIS Seminar, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- 1980's Project of Council on Foreign Relations, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- NEH Fellowship, 1977-78, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- The Luce Grant, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- The Burton Investigation, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- AS 602, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Federal Reserve Bulletin: Problems Facing Post-Treaty Japan, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Papers Read at Meetings; Programs, 1957-1969 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Reviews: The U.S. and the Philippines, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Miscellaneous Publications, 1966, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Tabulation or Philippine Laws in Preemptive Session of 1907 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Reviews of the Philippines: Public Policy and National Economic Development, 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Philippine Studies: v. 4, #3, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Pacific Affairs: Economic Consequences of the Philippines Trade Act", 1955 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Philippine Sociological Review: Economic Aspects of Philippine Agrarian Reform, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Philippine Law Journal: The Case for Peso Devaluation, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Philippine-American Affairs: The Case for Disengagement, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Entrepreneurship and Economic Development in the Philippines, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- The Nature of Philippine Economic Nationalism, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Southeast Asia: An Economist's Viewpoint, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Revised Trade Agreement, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- The Quirino Administration in Perspective, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Commercial Policy and Economic Nationalism, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Miscellaneous Publications, 1952, 1954, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Philippines-American Affairs, 1966-1967, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Diaries and Notebooks, 1958-1981 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Xeroxing Orders, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Jim Nach: The Philippines in Viet Nam, 1954-1966, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Jim Nach: The Philippine Statehood Movement of 1971-1972, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Decision for War (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- The Imperial Decision, 1898-1899 and Antecedents (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Imperialism at Bay, 1900-1902 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Taking Up the Burden, 1902-1909 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- End of the Taft Era (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Passage of the Jones Law, 1913-1916 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Tension and Tumult, 192101926 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Eve of Independence, 1927-1931 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
- Decision for Independence, 1932-1935 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
- The Philippine Commonwealth, 1935-1941 (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
- War Comes to the Philippines, 1939-1942 (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
- Government in Exile, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- The Transfer of Power, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 18-20)
- Golay: Ms. Chapters 7, 8, 9 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Footnotes to Chapters 10, 11, 12; pages 28-44 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- The Commonwealth, 1935-1940 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Chapter II - The Commonwealth, 1935-1940 - Footnotes (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Chapter 2: Imperialism at Bay, 1899-1902 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Philippines: Agricultural Calculations (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Agricultural Development Policy (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Rice Self-Suffiency, 1910 to Present (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Research Notes: Philippine-American Relations (Box 3, Folder 29-30)
- Commonwealth - Articles (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Search for Security, Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Philippines: Settlement of Veterans Claims (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Commonwealth (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Basic Agricultural Data: Land Colonization (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Minor Traditional Exports, 1947-1967 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- P{hilippines: Value of Principal Exports, 1899-1940 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- War Overtakes the Philippines, 1940-1942 (Box 3, Folder 38-39)
- War Overtakes the Philippines, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 40-41)
- Government in Exile, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 42-43)
- Commonwealth (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
- Commonwealth, Part II (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
- Commonwealth, Part III (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
- Commonwealth, Part IV (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
- Correspondence from Filipino Friends, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Filipinos Confront Independence, 1928-1931 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
- The Philippine Independence Movement, 1898-1899 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
- The Philippine Independence Movement, 1899-1902 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- The Philippine Independence Movement, 1902-1907 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- The Philippine Independence Movement, 1909-1916 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- The Philippine Independence Movement, 1927-1931 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- The Philippine Independence Movement (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Philippine Commission, Annual Reports, 1904-1906 (for earlier reports, see "Taft as Governor" file) (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Philippine Commission, Annual Reports, 1906-1907 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Philippine Commission, Annual Reports, 1908-1910 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Philippine Commission, Annual Reports (Box 4, Folder 23)
- The Payne-Aldrich Rariff, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Public Land Policy (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Education Policy (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Philippines Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Bureau of Insular Affairs [BIA] - Events of 1903-1908 (Box 4, Folder 28-30)
- Mining Policy (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Monetary and Banking Policy (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Benquet Road and Baquio (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Forestry Policy (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Manila Americans (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Philippine Constitutional Law (Box 4, Folder 36)
- BIA - The End of the Taft Era, 1910-1912 (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
- BIA - Transition to Democracy Party Rule, 1913-1914 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- BIA - The 3rd Jones Bill, 1915-1916 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Harrison Administration, Post Jones, 1916-1921 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- BIA Files - Wood Adminstration, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Wood's Diary Entries, 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Government Under the Republicans, 1921-1929 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- BIA Files - Fairfield Bill (Box 4, Folder 45-47)
- Wood Administration, Post-Fairfield Bill (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Eve of Independence, 1927-1931 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Q's [Manuel Quézon] Report to the Legislature. Fall, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Independence Achieved, 1932-1935 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Independence Achieved, 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
- Other Items on T.R. Jr's [Theodore Roosevelt] Administration (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Golay Connection (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Genealogy - Obituaries (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Genealogy - Hindman Materials (Wills, Estates, etc.) (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Genealogy - Records of Military Service (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Genealogy - Xeroxed materials from Odell book) (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Genealogy - Miscellaneous Golay materials (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Genealogy - The Virginia Connection (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Genealogy - The Massachusetts/New York/Indiana Connection (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Genealogy materials (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Golay Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 16-22)